<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on From System to System</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on From System to System</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite and Least Favorite Aspects of R</title>
      <link>/2018/08/12/my-favorite-and-least-favorite-aspects-of-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/12/my-favorite-and-least-favorite-aspects-of-r/</guid>
      <description>In September 2015, as I started working in a lab that requires bioinformatics skills, I made a new friend whose name is R. Before then, the last time I programmed was in 2007 or 2008, in C, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t do well in it. Then, R has become my de facto mother tongue in programming. Three years later, I&amp;rsquo;m on my way of developing a new R package for spatial transcriptomics1, and I have fixed bugs in other bioinformatics packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best and Worst Parts of Being Autistic</title>
      <link>/2018/08/09/the-best-and-worst-parts-of-being-autistic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/08/09/the-best-and-worst-parts-of-being-autistic/</guid>
      <description>I have debated for a while whether I should write this post. Eventually I decided to write it, since first, even if it may harm my opportunities of employment after I graduate, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to work with someone who discriminates against autistics anyway because passing as neurotypical is very stressful; I need to reserve my energy for the real cool work. Second, we need to make the positive aspects of autism more well-known to reduce discrimination and increase acceptance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lorenz attractor animation (gganimate)</title>
      <link>/2018/07/29/lorenz-attractor-animation-gganimate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/29/lorenz-attractor-animation-gganimate/</guid>
      <description>I have previously written about making the iconic Lorenz attractor animation with plotly; see that previous post for what the Lorenz system is. In the UseR! conference this year, Thomas Lin Pedersen presented the brand new version of gganimate which implements a grammar of animation, much like the grammar of graphics in ggplot2. In the older version by David Robinson, animation was made by adding an aes called frame. Now it’s just like adding geom_*s, scale_*s, stat_*s, and etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lorenz attractor animation (Plotly)</title>
      <link>/2018/07/28/lorenz-attractor-animation-plotly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/28/lorenz-attractor-animation-plotly/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post in this blog.
## [1] &amp;quot;Hello World!&amp;quot; Once for a class assignment, we were asked to control the Lorenz system. The instructor recommended us to use MATLAB for assignments, but since I’m inexperienced in MATLAB, I decided to use R to do the assignments, and used the package plotly to make interactive 3D plots of phase portraits1 of the Lorenz system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources for science and religion</title>
      <link>/2018/07/28/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/28/resources/</guid>
      <description>Here are some resources on dialogues between science and religion across faiths that I found helpful. I have chosen resources that support mainstream science and have intellectual rigor. Note that while these resources all seem to oppose the common belief that science and religion are in essential conflict and cannot be reconciled (a.k.a. the conflict thesis), this does not imply a bias in favor of religion. Historians of science have discredited the conflict thesis in recent decades, though this development have not gone far beyond the academia.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>